<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>London AFOLs Blog</title>
		<link>https://londonafols.uk/blog/</link>
		<description>London AFOLs Blog</description>
		<category>Model Building</category>
		<copyright>Copyright (C) 2020 London AFOLs. All rights reserved.</copyright>
		<language>en-gb</language>
		<atom:link href="https://londonafols.uk/blog/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>Habitat Meetup - June 2020</title>
			<link>https://londonafols.uk/blog/2020/06/24/habitat-meetup---june-2020/</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://londonafols.uk/blog/2020/06/24/habitat-meetup---june-2020/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>The theme of this month’s meet-up was minifig habitats. Minifig habitats are 8x8x8 vignettes built around a particular minifig or set of minifigs and built in a way that allows them to be interlocked and stacked together.
</p><p>Our resident leader of the habitat movement, <a href="https://www.instagram.com/cazmockett/">Caz Mockett</a> kicked things off by showing her extensive collection of habitats. We spent the rest of the meet-up socialising, building our own habitats and finishing with a show-and-tell.
</p><p>An example of the fantastic creativity this format allows is evident in these three habitats built by <a href="https://www.instagram.com/brickmasterryan/">Ryan Harkin</a>:
<img src="https://londonafols.uk//blog/media/habitat-meetup-june-2020/habitats.jpg" alt="Photo of three Minifig Habitats by Ryan Harkin" />
</p><p>The meetup was covered in more depth on our Instagram:
</p><p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CA_WTgGJqXK/">How to build a Minifig Habitat</a></p><p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CBeLdJ7JHYN/">Habitat meetup builds 1</a></p><p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CBgsc8MphZC/">Habitat meetup builds 2</a></p><p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CBjG3KSpCo1/">Habitat meetup builds 3</a></p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>A Set Back in Time 1970-79</title>
	<link>https://londonafols.uk/blog/2020/05/31/a-set-back-in-time-1970-79/</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://londonafols.uk/blog/2020/05/31/a-set-back-in-time-1970-79/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p><em>This is part three of a series by one of our resident Lego history buffs, <a href="https://twitter.com/marcsellopapa">Marton Ferenci</a>, who is keeping sane during lockdown by featuring great sets from Lego's past. Don't miss his pick of sets from the <a href="https://londonafols.uk/blog/">50s</a> and <a href="https://londonafols.uk/blog/">60s</a>.</em></p><p>The 1970s was the decade following the Moon landing - an achievement commemorated in plastic on many occasions, even to this day. My visit to the Vault (where the company has an original copy of almost every set released) allowed me to hold some of the early sets connected with the Moon landing and it also heavily influenced my personal picks. Every time I look at these they transport me back to that day.
</p><p><img src="https://londonafols.uk//blog/media/set-back-in-time/SpaceModule.jpg" alt="A photo of set 367 - Space Module - preserved in the Vault" />
</p><p>A small aside on the Vault: the Lego Group is a company seriously committed to preserving the history of the company and how it all came about. Not a lot people are aware but they actually have an entire team tasked with archiving their products and history.
</p><p>I don't really get when people complain about the lack of originality in modern Lego sets and feel originality was a thing of the past. If we look more carefully we can see that themes have used and reused ideas, sets and vehicles in almost every single decade and there is nothing wrong with that - sets evolve, designs are upgraded but Lego always stay true to the original.
</p><p>Compare set  <a href="https://brickset.com/sets/367-1/Space-Module-with-Astronauts">Space Module</a> with the <a href="https://brickset.com/sets/10266-1/NASA-Apollo-11-Lunar-Lander">Lunar Lander</a> released recently.
</p><p>Both of them depict the same historical event, both are deeply charming, yet their designs differ widely and both can happily coexist on a proud collector's shelf.
</p><p><img src="https://images.brickset.com/sets/images/367-1.jpg" alt="Box art of set 367 - Space Module" />
<img src="https://images.brickset.com/sets/images/10266-1.jpg" alt="Box art of set 10266 - Lunar Lander" />
</p><p>The period 1970-74 gave us <a href="https://brickset.com/sets/theme-Minitalia">Minitalia</a>, <a href="https://brickset.com/sets/078-1/Roadway-Base-Plate-50X50">suburban baseplates (078)</a>, <a href="https://brickset.com/sets/theme-Trains/subtheme-12V">12V trains</a> coexisting with <a href="https://brickset.com/sets/theme-Trains/subtheme-4-5V">4.5V trains</a>, vehicles widths that were variously 4, 6 and 8 studs wide and of course... fully moulded vehicles.
</p><p><img src="https://londonafols.uk//blog/media/set-back-in-time/MouldedCars.jpg" alt="Various Lego cars displayed in the Lego House" />
</p><p><a href="https://brickset.com/sets/theme-Samsonite/subtheme-Jumbo-Bricks">Jumbo bricks</a> and the <a href="https://brickset.com/sets/theme-Homemaker">Homemaker</a> theme were things. Who can forget those <a href="https://brickset.com/sets/tag-Maxifig">maxifigs</a>?
</p><p><img src="https://londonafols.uk//blog/media/set-back-in-time/Homemaker.jpg" alt="Various Homemaker sets on display in the Lego Ideas House" />
</p><p>We also had semi-neat storage boxes (<a href="https://brickset.com/sets/query-5324">791-794</a>). I'm semi-excited by the Lego-IKEA collaboration but at the time of writing we still have no idea what form it will take.
</p><p>Floating hulls were first introduced in this period so my pick for this period must certainly be the <a href="https://brickset.com/sets/1650-1/Maersk-Line-Container-Ship">Maersk Line Container Ship</a></p><p><img src="https://images.brickset.com/sets/images/1650-1.jpg?201012240713" alt="Box art of set 1650 - Maersk Line Container Ship" />
</p><p>It was a hard choice because so many amazing <a href="https://brickset.com/sets/query-5326">Town</a> sets came to life in this period but overall I feel that this Maersk set is more collectible... oh and the hue of that blue! While technically you could take all your (non-electric) Lego sets to the bathtub, the Maersk Line Container Ship was an ocean of fun...
</p><p>This may seem like a very specific time frame to focus on but there is a good reason for that. These three years featured a real boom in the number of new sets produced by Lego. Particularly noteable were the <a href="https://brickset.com/sets/theme-Hobby-Set">Hobby Set</a> vehicles featuring brands such as Norton, Harley Davidson, Renault and Cadillac.
</p><p><img src="https://londonafols.uk//blog/media/set-back-in-time/Formula.jpg" alt="Set 392 on display in the Lego Ideas House" />
</p><p>Maxifigs still reigned supreme but a new hero was on the horizon, slowly closing in... without legs or arms at least initially!
</p><p><img src="https://londonafols.uk//blog/media/set-back-in-time/MinifigStudy.jpg" alt="Experimental models of the minifigure displayed in the Lego House" />
</p><p>The highlight for me from this period was the 1977 <a href="https://brickset.com/sets/theme-Technic/year-1977">debut of Technic</a> and so my pick must be the <a href="https://brickset.com/sets/853-1/Car-Chassis">Car Chassis</a></p><p><img src="https://images.brickset.com/sets/images/853-1.jpg" alt="Box art of set 853 - Car Chassis" />
</p><p>Lego <a href="https://brickset.com/sets/tag-Super-Car">Super cars</a> are still a thing - the <a href="https://brickset.com/sets/42115-1/Lamborghini-Sián-FKP-37">Lamborghini Sián</a> was released just this week. These days, however, they are much more about the chassis than the tech underneath. It's impressive that the Technic theme is still, to this day, coming up with some fascinating pieces of machinery.
</p><p>Major milestone reached! It's the dawn of the minifigure and who would've known that they would go on to conquer the planet and outnumber humanity?
</p><p>Sadly 2020 marks the passing of the father of them all, Jens Nygaard Knudsen. A touching collection of thoughts and farewells by fellow Lego designers were collected on the <a href="http://thebrickblogger.com/2020/02/in-memory-of-lego-designer-jens-nygaard-knudsen/">Brick Blogger</a> and is worth more than a moment of your time to read and reflect on. Don't forget you can share your commemorative builds with the <a href="https://www.instagram.com/explore/tags/nygaardmemorialfleet/">#NygaardMemorialFleet</a> on Instagram.
</p><p>My pick for this year could easily have been one that featured the minifig - how about <a href="https://brickset.com/sets/375-2/Castle">that</a> castle or something in yummy <a href="https://brickset.com/sets/theme-Space/year-1979">Classic Space</a>?
</p><p><img src="https://londonafols.uk//blog/media/set-back-in-time/Vault.jpg" alt="Information fliers posted in the Vault" />
</p><p>No, instead I'm going to go with this. It's the swansong of the <a href="https://brickset.com/sets/theme-Hobby-Set">Hobby Set</a> line and is an early predecessor of <a href="https://brickset.com/sets/theme-Creator-Expert">Creator Expert</a>. It's the <a href="https://brickset.com/sets/398-1/USS-Constellation">USS Constellation</a></p><p><img src="https://images.brickset.com/sets/images/398-1.jpg" alt="Box art of Set 398 - USS Constellation" />
</p><p>The high part count for this set comes from it being entirely brick built (actually mostly plate built!) It's also one of the first sets meant for display rather than focusing on play. Some trivia on this set: Lego re-released it in 2003 as set <a href="https://brickset.com/sets/10021-1/USS-Constellation">10021</a>.
</p><p>There is so much low hanging Lego fruit in 1979 but this little set captured my interest the most as it resonates with one of my most recent Lego experiences! Can you make the connection? Behold the Scala <a href="https://brickset.com/sets/313-2/Bracelet-and-Pendant">Bracelet and Pendant</a> or should we call it <a href="https://brickset.com/sets/theme-Dots">DOTS</a> beta?
</p><p><img src="https://images.brickset.com/sets/images/313-2.jpg" alt="Box art of Set 313 - Bracelet and Pendant" />
</p><p>Many of my good friends from London AFOLs were instrumental in building the <a href="https://www.lego.com/en-gb/aboutus/news/2020/january/lego-dots/">House of Dots</a> in London for the launch (or re-launch?) of the jewellry line. The experimental showroom designed by French artist <a href="https://www.camillewalala.com">Camille Walala</a> was the perfect setting and the team did an awesome job in building this dream house. Our very own <a href="https://twitter.com/mstudman">Michael Studman</a> wrote a great review on <a href="http://www.newelementary.com/2020/02/lego-dots-new-pieces-opalescence.html">New Elementary</a> about the experience!
</p><p><img src="https://londonafols.uk//blog/media/set-back-in-time/HouseOfDots.jpg" alt="Interior of the House of Dots" />
</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Member Spotlight Caz Mockett Lego House</title>
	<link>https://londonafols.uk/blog/2020/05/28/member-spotlight-caz-mockett-lego-house/</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://londonafols.uk/blog/2020/05/28/member-spotlight-caz-mockett-lego-house/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>In 2019 one of our most active members, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/BlockHeadUK">Caz Mockett</a>, (also known as Madam Mayor of Micropolis) was chosen as one of a select group of AFOLs to exhibit her work in the <a href="https://legohouse.com/">Lego House</a>'s Masterpiece Gallery.
</p><p>Here Stuart Harris, Master Builder of the Lego House, interviews Caz.
</p><p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/FNohe-etuHQ" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></p><p>Another of our members, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCMFk9ud6WdxSpePi0cVfYjw">Matt Elder</a>, also interviewed Caz recently about being chosen for the Lego House Masterpiece Gallery.
</p><p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/6HXUPYKIDCA" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></p><p>Well done Caz!
</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>A Set Back in Time 1960-69</title>
	<link>https://londonafols.uk/blog/2020/05/20/a-set-back-in-time-1960-69/</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://londonafols.uk/blog/2020/05/20/a-set-back-in-time-1960-69/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p><em>This is part two of a series by one of our resident Lego history buffs, <a href="https://twitter.com/marcsellopapa">Marton Ferenci</a>, who is keeping sane during lockdown by featuring great sets from Lego's past.</em></p><p><strong>1960-69 <a href="https://brickset.com/sets/116-1/Starter-Train-Set-with-Motor">Starter Train Set with Motor</a></strong><img src="https://images.brickset.com/sets/images/116-1.jpg" alt="Image of set 116 - Starter Train Set with Motor" />
</p><p>Another day, another decade gone - worry not I will slow down eventually, unlike this beauty which has just began moving! It was not an easy pick with the dawn of amazing buildings and bigger sets like 080, imagine the pricing of that one today...
</p><p>This photo I took from the Lego Ideas House features set 116 and is how my ideal playroom would've looked like in 1969.
<img src="https://londonafols.uk//blog/media/set-back-in-time/60sTrains.jpg" alt="60s trains" />
</p><p>The story continues next time... but we aren't quite at the Ideas Saturn V yet!
</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>A Set Back in Time 1950-59</title>
	<link>https://londonafols.uk/blog/2020/05/19/a-set-back-in-time-1950-59/</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://londonafols.uk/blog/2020/05/19/a-set-back-in-time-1950-59/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p><em>This is first in a series of posts by one of our resident Lego history buffs, <a href="https://twitter.com/marcsellopapa">Marton Ferenci</a>, who is keeping sane during lockdown by featuring great sets from Lego's past.</em></p><p><strong>1950-59 <a href="https://brickset.com/sets/700_0-1/Gift-Package">Gift Package</a></strong><img src="https://images.brickset.com/sets/images/700_0-1.jpg" alt="Image of set 700_0 - Gift Package" />
</p><p>My inspiration for this series obviously came from the joy that is brought to us by Brickset's <a href="https://brickset.com/news/category-Random-set">Random set of the day</a> and <a href="https://brickset.com/news/category-Featured-set">Featured set of the day</a>. To keep myself sane and taking it to another level I decided to revisit the history of the Lego Group and highlight one set from a given time period.
</p><p>I was lucky enough to participate in the Lego Inside Tour back in 2018 - one of my favourite parts was visiting the Lego Ideas House (usually not open to the public) which has an extended version of the history exhibition found in the basement of the Lego House.
</p><p>Brick history started in 1949 with the Automatic Binding Bricks but I have started my timeline a year later with the Gift Package set.
</p><p>It is my favourite set from the first decade of Lego, it has absolutely everything you need and way too many flags :) The magnificent garage door, the lights. Those trees. Old school windows. Printed bricks. The Town Plan hosted non-brick vehicles however there was a certain charm in those, a sort of transition from the past. And very familiar looking child models! (one of whom ended up being the CEO of TLG...)
</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Welcome</title>
	<link>https://londonafols.uk/blog/2020/05/18/welcome/</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://londonafols.uk/blog/2020/05/18/welcome/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Welcome the London AFOLs Blog and our very first blog post.
</p><p>London AFOLs is a group of Adult Fans of Lego who live in or near London. We meet once a month in a pub in Euston (or on Zoom at present) and play with, chat about and generally geek out about our common interest - Lego. Membership is free and everyone is welcome. You can join and find more information about us on <a href="https://www.meetup.com/LondonAFOLs">Meetup.com</a>.
</p><p>Many of our members are prolific Lego MOC builders. Some have encyclopaedic knowledge of particular Lego themes. Others are technical wizards when it comes to Lego building techniques. So we thought a blog to promote their MOCs, ideas, research and knowledge would be a useful thing.
</p><p>We hope you enjoy all the exciting content we plan to bring you!
</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
