<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>London AFOLs Blog</title>
		<link>https://londonafols.uk/blog/</link>
		<description>London AFOLs Blog</description>
		<category>Model Building</category>
		<copyright>Copyright (C) 2020 London AFOLs. All rights reserved.</copyright>
		<language>en-gb</language>
		<atom:link href="https://londonafols.uk/blog/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>Member Spotlight Caz Mockett Lego House</title>
			<link>https://londonafols.uk/blog/2020/05/28/member-spotlight-caz-mockett-lego-house/</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://londonafols.uk/blog/2020/05/28/member-spotlight-caz-mockett-lego-house/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>In 2019 one of our most active members, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/BlockHeadUK">Caz Mockett</a>, (also known as Madam Mayor of Micropolis) was chosen as one of a select group of AFOLs to exhibit her work in the <a href="https://legohouse.com/">Lego House</a>'s Masterpiece Gallery.
</p><p>Here Stuart Harris, Master Builder of the Lego House, interviews Caz.
</p><p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/FNohe-etuHQ" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></p><p>Another of our members, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCMFk9ud6WdxSpePi0cVfYjw">Matt Elder</a>, also interviewed Caz recently about being chosen for the Lego House Masterpiece Gallery.
</p><p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/6HXUPYKIDCA" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></p><p>Well done Caz!
</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>A Set Back in Time 1960-69</title>
	<link>https://londonafols.uk/blog/2020/05/20/a-set-back-in-time-1960-69/</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://londonafols.uk/blog/2020/05/20/a-set-back-in-time-1960-69/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p><em>This is part two of a series by one of our resident Lego history buffs, <a href="https://twitter.com/marcsellopapa">Marton Ferenci</a>, who is keeping sane during lockdown by featuring great sets from Lego's past.</em></p><p><strong>1960-69 <a href="https://brickset.com/sets/116-1/Starter-Train-Set-with-Motor">Starter Train Set with Motor</a></strong><img src="https://images.brickset.com/sets/images/116-1.jpg" alt="Image of set 116 - Starter Train Set with Motor" />
</p><p>Another day, another decade gone - worry not I will slow down eventually, unlike this beauty which has just began moving! It was not an easy pick with the dawn of amazing buildings and bigger sets like 080, imagine the pricing of that one today...
</p><p>This photo I took from the Lego Ideas House features set 116 and is how my ideal playroom would've looked like in 1969.
<img src="https://londonafols.uk/blog/media//blog/media/60sTrains.jpg" alt="60s trains" />
</p><p>The story continues tomorrow... but we aren't quite at the Ideas Saturn V yet!
</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>A Set Back in Time 1950-59</title>
	<link>https://londonafols.uk/blog/2020/05/19/a-set-back-in-time-1950-59/</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://londonafols.uk/blog/2020/05/19/a-set-back-in-time-1950-59/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p><em>This is first in a series of posts by one of our resident Lego history buffs, <a href="https://twitter.com/marcsellopapa">Marton Ferenci</a>, who is keeping sane during lockdown by featuring great sets from Lego's past.</em></p><p><strong>1950-59 <a href="https://brickset.com/sets/700_0-1/Gift-Package">Gift Package</a></strong><img src="https://images.brickset.com/sets/images/700_0-1.jpg" alt="Image of set 700_0 - Gift Package" />
</p><p>My inspiration for this series obviously came from the joy that is brought to us by Brickset's <a href="https://brickset.com/news/category-Random-set">Random set of the day</a> and <a href="https://brickset.com/news/category-Featured-set">Featured set of the day</a>. To keep myself sane and taking it to another level I decided to revisit the history of the Lego Group and highlight one set from a given time period.
</p><p>I was lucky enough to participate in the Lego Inside Tour back in 2018 - one of my favourite parts was visiting the Lego Ideas House (usually not open to the public) which has an extended version of the history exhibition found in the basement of the Lego House.
</p><p>Brick history started in 1949 with the Automatic Binding Bricks but I have started my timeline a year later with the Gift Package set.
</p><p>It is my favourite set from the first decade of Lego, it has absolutely everything you need and way too many flags :) The magnificent garage door, the lights. Those trees. Old school windows. Printed bricks. The Town Plan hosted non-brick vehicles however there was a certain charm in those, a sort of transition from the past. And very familiar looking child models! (one of whom ended up being the CEO of TLG...)
</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Welcome</title>
	<link>https://londonafols.uk/blog/2020/05/18/welcome/</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://londonafols.uk/blog/2020/05/18/welcome/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Welcome the London AFOLs Blog and our very first blog post.
</p><p>London AFOLs is a group of Adult Fans of Lego who live in or near London. We meet once a month in a pub in Euston (or on Zoom at present) and play with, chat about and generally geek out about our common interest - Lego. Membership is free and everyone is welcome. You can join and find more information about us on <a href="https://www.meetup.com/LondonAFOLs">Meetup.com</a>.
</p><p>Many of our members are prolific Lego MOC builders. Some have encyclopaedic knowledge of particular Lego themes. Others are technical wizards when it comes to Lego building techniques. So we thought a blog to promote their MOCs, ideas, research and knowledge would be a useful thing.
</p><p>We hope you enjoy all the exciting content we plan to bring you!
</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
